<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Type and Values on Ballerina Coding Tips</title><link>http://bal.tips/docs/types/</link><description>Recent content in Type and Values on Ballerina Coding Tips</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://bal.tips/docs/types/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Values</title><link>http://bal.tips/docs/types/values/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bal.tips/docs/types/values/</guid><description>Ballerina Value Universe The universe of Ballerina is composed of a variety of value types, forming the backbone of this robust programming language. Data values include fundamental types such as int, boolean, and string. Structured values encompass arrays, lists, maps, and records, providing a rich platform for data organization. Behavior values, including functions, objects, and services, underpin dynamic interactions within the language. This expansive spectrum of values is what elevates Ballerina to its status as a powerful tool in programming.</description></item><item><title>Boolean Data Type</title><link>http://bal.tips/docs/types/simple/boolean/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bal.tips/docs/types/simple/boolean/</guid><description>Boolean Data Type The Boolean data type represents boolean truth values: true and false. You may use boolean values to represent various conditions in your program. For example, you can use a boolean value to represent whether a file exists or not, whether a user is logged in or not, etc. Use-cases of boolean values are endless.
✍ Syntax boolean
✍ Syntax Boolean type is written as boolean. We use the Boolean literal syntax to write Boolean values.</description></item><item><title>Float Data Type</title><link>http://bal.tips/docs/types/simple/float/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bal.tips/docs/types/simple/float/</guid><description>Float Data Type The Float data type represents 64-bit IEEE 754-2008 binary floating point numbers. Floating point numbers are used to represent fractional values. They are suitable for scientific and engineering calculations.
Floating point values do not provide exact precision. Hence, they are not suitable for financial and monetary calculations. For such calculations, you can use the Decimal type.
✍ Syntax float
✍ Syntax The floating point type is written as float.</description></item><item><title>Decimal Data Type</title><link>http://bal.tips/docs/types/simple/decimal/</link><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://bal.tips/docs/types/simple/decimal/</guid><description>Decimal Data Type The Decimal basic data type represents 128-bit IEEE 754-2008 decimal floating point values. Decimals in Ballerina provide higher precision and a larger range of values than floating-point numbers. Which means, they are suitable for financial and monetary calculations.
✍ Syntax decimal
✍ Syntax The decimal type is written as decimal. You can use Floating Point Literal to represent a decimal value. Please note that you cannot use hexadecimal floating point literals with decimal type.</description></item></channel></rss>